[music]
>> Um, want to acknowledge all the pastors
that are here. Minister Pish,
uh, [music] Pastor Ronnie,
uh, Pastor Rashid with your wife.
I was told
the language has now changed.
You no longer call us babe, you call us
the supreme leader.
That's the official language, Pastor
Kevin.
So, the supreme leader, Pastor Rashid.
Someone will get the joke tomorrow.
I also want to appreciate the wife of
Pastor Ken Jogu,
uh, Pastor Kanjago with your wife,
Pastor William, thank you for leading
us. Pastor Anita,
thank you for the amazing job in the one
soul movement.
Pastor Kevin with your wife,
uh, Kibali's wife, may God bless you.
Pastor Liz,
let's celebrate the men and women of
God.
>> [applause]
>> I also want to acknowledge the presence
of my wife,
the supreme leader.
Amen.
May God bless you.
You know, today Pastor Kevin told me
something very very powerful. He didn't
know,
but I
I began to meditate on it. He told me,
"You know, men make houses,
but women make homes."
And so, when you have a woman that is
not cultured [music]
and who has no patience, she will
destroy the home.
And I remember I told him,
"There's one virtue that every mother
and woman needs.
Women [music] grow progressively,
but men grow in stages."
Hallelujah. It's not in my sermon.
It's part of our wisdom.
Women [music] grow progressively. That's
why
a woman can be 30 years, but what
happened to her when she was 16
will still have effect in her 30. The
emotions connected.
But a man moves from one box to another.
So, it takes a mature woman to be
patient with a man
to outgrow a certain box.
That box can be called soccer.
It takes a lot of patience to be patient
with that man until he outgrows that
box.
And then when you when you when you
enter in life, you discover
the older the marriage the more
submitted the man is to the woman.
If you want to know that people have
been married for long, is a man will be
given the microphone and he will give
his wife. And after the wife has spoken,
the man will say, "You know, my wife
have said everything."
Because they now reach a place and they
discover not only did I marry somebody,
but this person became patient with
every [music] stage of my life, which I
doubt there was anyone else was going to
be patient with this. So, if you're
sitting next to a woman, tell that
woman, "Receive the virtue of patience."
Hallelujah.
Amen. Let's go to the word today.
We Last Sunday, we checked on what we
call them
the fivefold.
Um I remember someone told me, "This
year, pastor, I want to grow
in God."
And what I What you need to understand
is that if you truly want to grow in
God, the Lord will [music] plant you
under the fivefold graces.
Because these are the maturing graces
according to Ephesians chapter number 10
from verse 12. From from chapter number
4 10 to 12.
And then we saw what I call the
eightfold structure that grows the
church
and it's order.
The eightfold structure.
And we saw that in second 1 Corinthians
chapter number 12 from 28
the structure there is first apostles.
First
apostles. That name first means proton,
the beginning anointing.
And we are seeing the Lord restoring the
fivefold.
Um
and we checked on the signs of an orphan
spirit. But today I want to speak on
what I call the mystery of the sheep.
The mystery of the sheep.
Anytime you are reading your Bible and
you come across an animal
as you're doing your Bible study
it is paramount to understand that there
is wisdom locked up in every animal.
So anytime the Lord mentions an animal
it is key to go beyond seeing the name
of the animal
it is important to research
and look in details concerning the
animal.
We see different animals mentioned in
the Bible.
And and and they represent different
things.
The eagle, the ox, the the serpent, the
lion. Why did Jesus call himself the
lion of the tribe of Judah?
And it is in that spirit that I want to
address the matter of why are we called
the sheep of the flock of the Lord.
Among all the animals, why is it that
the Lord just chose and said, "You know
what? I I'll not call my people I'll not
call them wild beast. I'll not call them
uh zebras. They're very beautiful, but
the name of a zebra in Kikuyu is one of
the worst names.
Waboi
Mchoro, you know zebra and you know they
they don't match.
Uh
what is a boy mchoro? What is that That
one is Yes?
Is a giraffe?
Is a waboi you're in trouble. Anyway,
>> [clears throat]
>> but all I'm trying to say is that there
is wisdom and there is reason why the
Lord chose a certain animal to express
certain truths.
Let us look at the book in the in 1
Chronicles chapter number 21 from verse
1.
The Bible speaks actually that the devil
um uh the devil incited. That's a very
powerful word. Now Satan stood up
against Israel and moved David to number
Israel. So, this is a story of David
doing a census.
According to the book of Deuteronomy,
a census was abolished or it was against
the law to count or number the people.
And the reason why the Lord was against
census
was because of the spirit behind census.
Anyone that numbered anything, he
communicated one thing. He is the owner
of what he's numbering.
He's the owner. But when it comes to now
monarchy system, a census censuses were
done so that you can know the number of
people that can fight in a battle.
So by the time you are counting the
people, it was a picture that you are
not believing and trusting in the
sufficiency of God when it comes to
victory.
So here David numbers Israel and the
Bible says says there that the devil
stood up. Some versions say that the
devil incited David to actually number
or do a census. There was an opposition
when you read that chapter.
There was a leader who was against the
census. But because the word of a king
supersedes the word of civilians, the
man said it's okay.
And the man performed the census.
AND ACCORDING TO THE CULTURE OF A
SHEPHERD, you could not number animals
that were not yours.
So he did the census from a place of
military understanding.
And this census attracted judgment.
Now the Lord had already GIVEN A DECREE
THAT THE PEOPLE should not agree to be
numbered.
So even THE PEOPLE BY THEM ACCEPTING TO
BE NUMBERED they were in error. And
that's why immediately after the census,
there was a plague that hit Israel. And
an angel was sent with a sword.
And many people died. But when you go to
chapter to verse 17 of 1 Chronicles,
there is a prayer that David made.
And that [clears throat] prayer is what
withheld the sword of the angel. And
David said to God, "Was it not I WHO
COMMANDED THE people to be numbered?" So
this was a command. It was not an
instruction. So the people were numbered
against their will. And then he
continues and says, "I am the one who
has sinned and done evil indeed." And
the Bible says, "BUT THESE SHEEP,
what have they done? LET YOUR HAND, I
PRAY, O Lord my God, be against me and
my father's house, but not against your
people that they should be proud." The
moment David positioned Israel as a
sheep,
THE LORD HAD TO WITHHOLD THE LOVE.
BECAUSE A SHEPHERD CANNOT [music] BECOME
a butcher.
Is someone getting me?
THE REASON WHY JUDGMENT FELL UPON ISRAEL
IS BECAUSE BY THEIR NUMBERING, THEY WERE
BEING positioned as men of war.
BUT IN THE REPENTANCE OF DAVID, HE WENT
AND RETURNED THE CHILDREN OF ISRAEL INTO
THEIR ORIGINAL ORDER. "THESE ARE NOT MY
ARMIES, but this IS THE FLOCK OF ELOHIM.
I DON'T OWN THE PEOPLE, but these people
[music] belong to God." That's why IN
THE ANCIENT CULTURE OF THE JEWS, A MAN
HAD AUTHORITY TO NUMBER his flock.
AND HE WOULD COUNT BECAUSE OUT OF
RESPONSIBILITY,
when you take the sheep outside to feed,
automatically you needed to know whether
all the sheep came back. So, there was a
CULTURE OF COUNTING. HOW DID JESUS KNOW
THAT THE ONE HAS LEFT and the 99 are? HE
ABANDONED THE 99. HOW did we come to the
number 99? It means the shepherd had
numbered every sheep.
And he knew the NUMBER OF SHEEP THAT HE
HAD. SO, WHEN DAVID RETURNED ISRAEL AS A
FLOCK TO THE LORD, THE LORD HAD TO MOVE
FROM THE THRONE OF JUDGMENT AND ENTER
THE THRONE OF A SHEPHERD.
AND A GOOD SHEPHERD LAYS HIS LIFE FOR
the people. A GOOD SHEPHERD CANNOT
[music] KILL the flock.
And the WRATH OF GOD WAS LIFTED.
ISAIAH CHAPTER NUMBER 53 AND VERSE SIX.
Isaiah chapter number 53 and verse six.
The Bible speaks clearly.
Isaiah 53 and verse six.
THE BIBLE SAYS, "ALL WE, like sheep,
have gone astray. WE HAVE TURNED
everyone to his own way.
AND THE LORD HAS laid on him the
iniquity
of us all."
The prophetic predisposition [music]
of Isaiah
is actually It is a language he's
talking. This is a prophet is a is a
messianic messianic prophecy.
BUT HE'S ALSO REFERRING THE PEOPLE that
Jesus died for as a sheep that has gone
astray. AND HE'S SAYING, "ACTUALLY, ALL
OF US [screaming] ARE LIKE SHEEP THAT
HAVE gone astray."
And the LANGUAGE OF A STRANGE SHEEP IS A
LANGUAGE of the sheep no longer feeds
where the master has allocated the
portion for feeding.
Going astray
is WHEN THE SHEEP NO LONGER FEEDS IN THE
IN THE demarcation in the parameters in
the jurisdiction of his feeding.
AND THE MOMENT THE CHILDREN OF ISRAEL
BEGAN TO FEED THE DOCTRINES OF THE
CANAANITES' GODS AND THE TEACHINGS OF
THE FOREIGN ENTITIES, THEY BEGAN to go
astray.
Now,
THE BIBLE SAYS THE JUDGMENT OF THE LAST
DAY will be the judgement of sheep and
goat.
Is that the Bible?
SO THE ONLY THING THAT A SHEEP can do is
GO ASTRAY.
A SHEEP CANNOT BECOME A GOAT.
So okay.
So so the people who believe in the goat
movement
I rather be in the sheep movement.
When people are becoming the goat, Messi
the goat, Pastor T the sheep.
Because in the last day it WILL BE A
CONTENTION OF GOATS
AND SHEEP.
And you see you need TO UNDERSTAND THAT
DNA OF A SHEEP IS different from that of
a goat.
SO SO WHEN YOU BECAME BORN AGAIN, THERE
WAS A NATURE THAT WAS IMPARTED IN YOU.
THAT NATURE SHIFTED everything and now
you have the nature of a sheep.
>> [snorts]
>> And what can happen to a sheep is go
astray
beyond the parameters OF FEEDING.
SO ANYTIME ISRAEL WENT ASTRAY, THE
SHEPHERD HAD TO COME AND RESTORE the
sheep back to the fold.
As we continue you will understand.
The language of the lost sheep
how we have read it is different from
backsliding.
It is a language of a sheep feeding
beyond the boundaries.
So you are a sheep.
>> [sighs]
>> But now you are reading the book of
Jasher.
You have gone beyond the 66 book
boundary.
So we need to bring you back.
Okay, we'll come to that.
Let's go slowly. Tell your neighbor,
"Neighbor,
sheep can go astray.
And that MEANS THEY ARE OUT OF THEIR
JURISDICTION.
MATTHEW CHAPTER NUMBER NINE, 35 to 38.
I'm just laying scriptural foundation.
Matthew chapter number nine, from verse
35 to 38.
We begin to see that that that
even Jesus himself looks at this and
he's very critical. Then Jesus went
about all the cities and villages.
Pastor Anita, teaching in their
synagogues, preaching the gospel of the
kingdom, and healing every sickness and
every disease among the people. You can
see the pattern. You don't begin by
healing. You begin by teaching.
Because the healing is supposed to be a
revelation of the teaching.
So, when people major on the healing
without the teaching, YOU MIGHT OPEN
A VERY STRANGE SPIRITUAL CENTER WHERE
MEN DON'T want the healer, but they want
the healing.
SO, WE MUST BRING THE CHURCH TO A PLACE
OF when you get healed AND THEY ASKED
YOU, "WHO HEALED YOU?" You can come with
the theology of Christ.
BUT YOU'RE NOT ENTERING THAT MAN SAID,
"WHAT I KNOW IS THAT I WAS BLIND, BUT
NOW I CAN SEE, BUT I DON'T KNOW WHO
HEALED ME." That is error.
SO, WE MUST TEACH AND THEN HEAL.
AND THERE ARE TIMES AS YOU ARE TEACHING,
HEALING IS HAPPENING.
Uh continue.
But when HE SAW THE MULTITUDES, HE was
moved with compassion for them.
Because they were weary and scattered
like sheep having no shepherd.
Continue.
Then he said to his disciples, "The
harvest
truly
is plentiful, but the laborers
are few." So, the problem is not the
harvest.
Let me help you, Pastor Anita and the
team that does soul winning.
When God is talking about SOUL WINNING,
THE LORD DOES NOT use the language of
volunteers.
>> [snorts]
>> He uses the language of laborers. This
is a commercial job. Meaning that there
are wages.
HE DOESN'T USE THE LANGUAGE OF SONS AND
PASTORS. THE LANGUAGE OF SOUL WINNING IS
LABOR.
A research was done. Bish.
The wealthiest ministry in TERMS OF
MONEY AND RESOURCES GLOBALLY IS A
ministry of a dead evangelist.
Evangelist Billy Graham. What was the
business of Billy Graham? Souls.
THE RESOURCES OF GOD are on the business
of God. And that is souls.
Because Jesus never died for brick and
mortar. Jesus died for men.
We can dwell there.
Do you know the Bible says he that
winneth souls is wise?
THERE ARE CERTAIN CROWNS
AND blessings that are tied to soul
winning.
And soul winning is not a business of
evangelists. You see, the day you got
born again, the Bible says, "And they
shall receive power. AND THE HOLY SPIRIT
SHALL COME UPON THEM. AND THEY
[clears throat] SHALL BECOME WITNESSES."
What What What are you witnessing? The
resurrected Christ.
You can witness WITH YOUR LIFE. YOU CAN
WITNESS WITH PREACHING, BUT EVERYONE
BORN AGAIN ACCORDING TO HEAVEN IS NOT A
CHRISTIAN. THE NAME CHRISTIAN WAS a
mockery word. It was the men of THE WAY.
THE NAME THAT JESUS GAVE THE CHURCH was
witnesses. CARRIERS OF EVIDENCE THAT
Jesus is not in the grave.
When I discovered this, if you need two
blessings, not in heaven, here. Win
souls.
THERE ARE THREE THERE ARE THREE
DIMENSIONS OF HARVEST.
There is
No, there is 30, 60, a hundredfold. That
scripture is in the book of Mark.
Where Peter asked, "What shall be given
of us who have abandoned all, even our
children and homes? What shall be given
of us?" When Jesus was speaking to the
rich young man when he told the rich
young man, "Go and sell all for the sake
of the kingdom and and then follow me."
And the young man refused and Jesus
said, "It is hard to enter the kingdom
of God." Then Peter stopped him and
asked him, "Then what will be given of
us who have abandoned all to follow
you?" And Jesus said, he categorizes I
wish we can get the scripture. He puts
them in two categories and he said,
"Them that have abandoned all for the
sake of the gospel and for the sake of
Christ, they shall receive their reward.
And then them that have abandoned all
with persecution SHALL RECEIVE A
HUNDREDFOLD IN this age."
Matthew 19:27-28. Give me the scripture
because we must deal with some matters
of people waiting for [music] people to
win souls, yet they are missing their
blessings.
Then he said to his disciples, "The
harvest" Matthew Matthew 19
Is it Matthew?
Matthew 19:27-29. So he said to him,
"Why do you call me good?" Then Peter
answered and said to him, everybody
read, "See, we have left all and
followed you. Therefore, what shall we
have?"
It is a conversation of we are laborers.
So, Jesus said to them, "ASSUREDLY
EVERYBODY READ, ASSUREDLY I SAY TO YOU
THAT IN THE REGENERATION, WHEN THE SON
OF MAN SITS ON THE THRONE of his glory,
you who have followed me also SIT ON 12
THRONES JUDGING THE 12 tribes of
Israel."
And everyone, let's all read.
Everyone who has left house OR BROTHERS
OR SISTERS OR FATHER OR MOTHER OR WIFE
OR CHILDREN OR LANDS, FOR WHAT? MY
NAME'S SAKE, SHALL RECEIVE A HUNDREDFOLD
AND AN INHERIT ETERNAL LIFE.
CONTINUE.
But
But many who are first will be last and
the last first.
Yes.
No, no, don't No, no, no.
Go back.
Yes.
But and everyone who has left
houses
brothers
sisters father mother
children
Why are you leaving? For the sake of the
gospel.
My name's sake, shall receive
a hundredfold. Are you seeing a
hundredfold?
And inherit
This a hundredfold is not heaven.
Is
in this time.
I can dwell there because many of us we
keep the faith to our hearts.
Huh.
There are times I'm always in the plane
going to a nation of people I don't
know.
But I'm reminded of this scripture, I
have left home,
brothers, sisters, father, mother. And
this one is hard, wife and children.
It's not easy.
>> [snorts]
>> And lands for my name's sake shall
receive a hundredfold. Tell your
neighbor, "Neighbor, the secret
of a hundredfold blessing
is soul winning."
Okay, where where how did we get there?
Matthew 9:35, Jesus look at the flock
and said, "This is a sheep without
shepherd." Now, let's look at Matthew
9:38 quickly. Oh, Jesus. Matthew 9:38,
today I have to finish. Therefore, pray
the Lord of harvest to send out laborers
into his harvest. So, he is the Lord of
harvest, but the Lord of harvest cannot
harvest for himself.
Can I confirm to you the mirror of this
story? Naomi, I mean, Ruth got married
to Boaz while in the harvest. And the
Bible called Boaz the Lord of THE
HARVEST. THE DEMAND of Ruth is that she
was in a foreign land, and according to
the law, she was considered as an
outcast. So, SHE IS IN A FOREIGN LAND.
The law does not [music] permit her to
be in the land. So, she cannot BE
EMPLOYED. BUT, AS SHE WAS LABORING IN
THE IN THE FIELD OF BOAZ, A TYPE of
Jesus. AS SHE WAS THERE LABORING, AND
NAOMI TOLD RUTH, "DO NOT LABOR in any
other field. Labor in this PARTICULAR
FIELD." AS SHE WAS LABORING THERE, FAVOR
LANDED ON HER. THE BIBLE SAYS, "EVEN THE
WORKERS BEGAN TO GIVE HER A CERTAIN
PORTION OF FEED FOOD." SHE WAS EVEN
PERMITTED TO DIP HER MORSEL OF BREAD IN
THE CUP OF WINE THAT BOAZ WAS PARTAKING
OF. AND AFTER THAT, SHE WAS MARRIED TO
THE LORD OF THE HARVEST BECAUSE THE
BIBLE CALLED BOAZ THE LORD OF THE
HARVEST. HER REWARD WAS GREATER. SO,
THIS IS A PICTURE IN THE OLD TESTAMENT
THAT THERE IS A REWARD IN TIME.
SHE WAS NOT REWARDED IN HEAVEN. SHE WAS
REWARDED. SHE GOT MARRIED TO THE LORD OF
THE HARVEST. I RELEASE THE GRACE for
soul winning. WHERE YOU ARE, THERE ARE
PEOPLE WHO NEED TO HEAR JESUS. WHERE YOU
ARE, THERE ARE PEOPLE THAT NEED TO HEAR
THE GOSPEL. THERE IS A LOST SHEEP THAT
NEEDS THE VOICE OF THE SHEPHERD TO COME
BACK TO THE FOLD.
Isaiah 40 and verse 11.
Let's go quickly.
Isaiah 40. He will feed his flock like a
shepherd. HE WILL GATHER THE LAMBS with
his ARM AND CARRY THEM IN HIS BOSOM AND
gently lead those who are with young.
This is how the Lord takes. The first
thing is that he will feed his flock
like a shepherd.
He will gather the lambs with his arms.
These are the young ones. They need to
be HANDLED CAREFULLY.
THERE ARE THOSE THAT ARE LED, BUT THERE
ARE THOSE that are handled.
Ezekiel chapter number 34 from verse 1
to 4.
THERE ARE FIVE TYPES OF flocks in the
house of God. Five.
THAT'S WHY I'M VERY SENSITIVE WHEN I
begin to grow spiritually lest I begin
to look down on some people
because these five are in the house of
God.
Ezekiel chapter number 34 from verse 1
to 4.
Ezekiel.
And the word of the Lord came to me
saying,
"Son of man,
prophesy
against the shepherds of Israel.
Prophesy and [clears throat] say to
them, "Thus says the Lord God to the
shepherds.
Woe, the name woe is a language of
judgment. Woe to the shepherds of Israel
who feed themselves.
SHOULD NOT THE SHEPHERDS FEED THE
FLOCKS?" Let me explain.
These meetings where a man gather mature
believers and they are exchanging
mysteries is an error. AND THEN THEY
LOOK DOWN UPON THE ONES THAT CAME IN THE
OTHER DAY AND they begin to treat them
as if they don't know what you're
talking about.
And it is a Pentecostal error where men
gather according to intensity of
revelations and then they look down upon
people who don't know what we know. One
day the Lord rebuked me sharply. I was
coming out of church and I FOUND A TEAM
of young people
lining up to go to F2 jump session AT
2:00.
CARRYING MY BIBLE
>> [screaming]
>> WITH A PHARISEE LOOK, I BEGAN TO LOOK AT
THEM AND SAY, "SINNERS. These guys I
wish they knew who God is, HOW MESSED UP
THEY ARE." THE HOLY SPIRIT rebuked me
AND TOLD ME, "ONE DAY YOU WERE LIKE
THEM. IT took the light of the gospel
for you to be changed." I repented.
HOW MANY TIMES HAVE YOU SEEN A DRUNKARD
DRIVING EARLY IN THE MORNING and you
look down upon them as if they are the
wicked of them all. That is a soul that
needs a shepherd. And the REASON WHY
THEY ARE NEXT TO YOU AND YOU KEEP ON
SEEING THEM IS BECAUSE YOU ARE MANDATED
TO WIN THEM TO JESUS. THEY WILL NOT COME
TO CHURCH. THE LORD HAS BROUGHT
proximity to you SO THAT YOU CAN SHARE
THE GOSPEL. BUT THE HYPOCRISY OF THE
BELIEVERS, WE KEEP ON GATHERING WITH
BROTHERS THAT HAVE THE SAME FIRE. YET
THE WORLD IS DYING WITHOUT JESUS.
THEY KEEP ON FEEDING THEMSELVES.
TABLES OF MYSTERIES AND DIMENSIONS AND
REALMS.
YET THERE ARE CHILDREN WHO don't
understand it.
A man came AND TOLD ME, "PASTOR, I KNOW
THERE ARE MANY PEOPLE FIGHTING YOU." I
TOLD HIM, "I KNOW."
And he told ME, "YOU KNOW,
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU TEACH, BUT I FEEL
I HEAR PEOPLE SAY SOME OF THE THINGS you
teach are not doctrinary, right?" I told
him, "Hold it there. The world has 8
billion people, eight."
The people that are The people that know
Jesus are 2 billion. 1 billion are
Catholics.
So, 6 billion don't even know the Bible.
SO, BEFORE WE ARGUE ON DOCTRINES, WE
HAVE EVEN missed on elementaries.
And the devil likes it when 50 people
are IN A CHURCH
WHEREAS THOUSANDS DON'T KNOW HIM.
I read this scripture, I felt rebuked.
Woe to the shepherds of Israel, who feed
themselves.
SO, THE SHEPHERDS HAVE NO PROBLEM. THEY
HAVE CAPACITY, they have revelation,
they have insights. I.
THEY HAVE DEPTHS, THEY HAVE MYSTERIES,
BUT THEY don't feed the flock.
Continue.
Who is this flock?
You eat the fat and clothe yourself with
the wool.
YOU SLAUGHTER THE FATLINGS, BUT YOU DO
not feed the flock.
Continue.
Are you seeing the the work of a
shepherd?
Number one, tell your Tell your
neighbor, "Membership number one,
the weak."
In this house, there are weak men and
women.
Please, when the Lord strengthens you,
remember the weak.
Remember the weak.
When the Lord lifts you and you're not
fighting certain battles, remember the
weak.
I.
>> [snorts]
>> When the Lord empowers you, remember the
weak.
Because they And this IS GOD'S FLOCK.
WHY DID HE BRING THE WEAK TO A SHEPHERD?
So that the weak can be strengthened,
not judged.
You strengthen the weak.
Can [snorts] I let you surprise you?
Every weak man has a strong part.
YOU CAN NEITHER DESIRE TO STAND AS A
SHEPHERD or a butcher.
AS A BUTCHER, YOU WILL EVEN KILL the
strong part.
But as a shepherd, you will strengthen
the weak
and enhance the strong. You know, even
in school, there are people who are good
in sciences, others are good in arts.
Others who are POOR IN ARTS, OTHERS were
good in sciences.
And when a teacher came, they will
acknowledge, at least you have
something.
Don't be like our old parents who used
to look at mathematics, physics, and
chemistry. And they will come to one
conclusion, you have failed. Yet you
have an A in theory. They don't know
you're an apostle in the making.
AND THEY WILL
THEY WILL MAKE YOU FEEL LIKE YOU DID
NOTHING. PLEASE TELL THAT NEIGHBOR,
NEIGHBOR,
every man that has a weakness,
there is a strong part.
Strengthen
the strong
and also strengthen the weak part.
We used to say in high school, let the
A's remain the A's, then begin to
improve the D's.
But you don't kill the D at the expense
of the A. Neither do you kill the A at
the expense of the D. Number two,
the weak you have not strengthened, nor
you heal those who are sick. So, number
two, we have the sick.
Fourth, praise the Lord.
Please, you can see a brother IN A SUIT
SPEAKING IN TONGUES, BUT HE'S SICK.
HE HAS CHILDHOOD WOUNDS.
RAISED WITHOUT A FATHER.
SO, DON'T BE DECEIVED BY HIS HAIRSTYLE,
SIDEBURNS, AND SUIT.
THAT MAN CAME BECAUSE HE'S SICK. AS A
PASTOR, MAYBE I KNOW HE'S IN HDU, HIGH
DEPENDENT UNIT.
BUT YOU YOU ARE LOOKING A HUSBAND, BUT
WE MUST TAKE HIM OUT OF HDU TO ICU TO
ORDINARY WARD BEFORE WE ALLOW HIM TO
DATE.
BUT YOU WANT TO DRAG A SICK MAN ON THE
ALTAR AND MARRY, AND THEN AFTER A FEW
YEARS YOU SAY, "WHO DID I MARRY?"
LISTEN, THE MAN CAME BECAUSE THE ALTAR
SEES THE LORD RELEASES THE SICK.
MHM.
SO, you are hearing a worshiper here
singing F sharp.
But she's sick.
You see, I'm not looking at the worship
team.
Peradventure, I look at one of them and
they think I'm prophesying.
And then you [music] come and pull a
worshiper and say I found a wife.
By the time you stay 2 years, you
discover I just got
someone who was
I would have allowed Pastor T to finish
with him and and and give me medical
reports so that I know if I have the
grace to continue with walking in her
healing or I wait for her to heal.
Please tell your brother there are sick
men here.
HEY.
AND THE LORD BRINGS THEM TO HIS HOUSE
AND PLANTS THEM UNDER A SHEPHERD. AND
GUESS WHAT HEALS, WHAT STRENGTHENS THE
WEAK? FEEDING. WHAT HEALS THE SICK?
FEEDING.
The Bible says not bound up the broken.
Number three, we have the broken.
We have the weak,
the sick,
the broken.
The broken. They're the house.
In the house.
Some of the broken are the strongest.
They're the ones who lead prayers in
diversity of tongues.
But when they step down,
they go back to their shell.
They're broken.
They wear masks, put on makeup,
put on mascara
with a fake secretary smile.
You know, one of the rules of becoming a
secretary, you are taught to smile even
when you're not happy.
Yeah, when we're working in the media,
we were told to fake it.
You'll go there and say,
"Welcome to Angaza Show."
And you have a heartbreak. Once you hear
they've gone off screen, you begin to
sow.
Then you go back, back to script.
So, we have people that are broken. They
are just They are good characters in the
script of life.
BUT ONCE THEY ARE DONE, when they get in
the changing room, which is their space,
where they cannot run away from
everyone, they have no strength to face
themselves.
AND SOME OF THEM EVEN WONDER, "WHY DO
PEOPLE ask me for advice?"
BECAUSE THEY HAVE THEY HAVE AN AURA OF
ATTRACTING MEN THAT ARE BROKEN, AND THEY
HAVE THE RIGHT SOLUTIONS, WHICH have
never worked for them. Am I shouting?
And they will go and ask the Lord,
"These things I'M SAYING,
HOW COME THEY ARE NOT APPLYING?"
THE CHURCH HAS broken people.
And guess what? IF YOU'RE A SHEPHERD of
such a church,
you have the weak,
you have the sick, YOU HAVE BROKEN.
AND THEN, LOOK AT THE NEXT ONE. "NOR
BROUGHT BACK WHAT WAS driven away."
What was driven away? We also have what?
Things and people that were driven away
because the head usher is part of them
that feed
themselves. They don't feed
the people.
So, the head usher usher
The head usher
And you know, now we are doing This is
now church.
has a problem with your dressing.
And I know you you you you are standing
at a very significant place at the door
and you represent the church
and she has a problem with the size and
the height
of your dress.
And she does not understand or he does
not understand your background.
That the day you told us to wear red
this is the closest I could get to red.
I I have no food. I'm trying to meet fit
in the church protocol.
But the way you are lectured, this is a
church of excellence. We don't entertain
mediocre. If you don't have uniform, you
better sit down. We serve from sacrifice
and that head usher is a manager who
update on the WhatsApp page is 2,000
money that you can miss for Sunday. That
2,000 is someone's prayer item for that
month.
Are we having church?
And so, THE PERSON SAYS, "INSTEAD OF
BEING THE ONE that ashameds the group, I
rather walk away."
In the name of excellence, we lost a
soul.
So, you you saw someone serving.
You you are a pastor's kid.
And you find one of the people serving
has a tattoo.
You begin to open the book of Leviticus.
And that person did not draw the tattoo
while in church. It was It was on the
person. Because that's a mark of their
testimony.
And you begin to say, "You know, the
people who serve pastors
should look like this."
But God has told us
not to drive men away,
but to restore them.
And if there is anyone watching online
and you are driven away, look for me.
Because I'm the shepherd.
>> [snorts]
>> Someone getting me?
Some of you are here, but you are driven
away.
It's not a language you didn't want to
serve. It's the way you are handled. And
I'm saying this church so that we can
understand.
And so that we can extend grace one to
another.
Let it never be captured that someone
left church because of you. This is not
to say that some people are not
hardheaded. Please, I know. There are
also people who are rude.
You agree YOU ARE WEARING WHITE.
AND ON SATURDAY AT 11:30 at night, they
say, "Must we wear white? Can we wear
blue?" And then they begin a whole
debate. And we are serving on Sunday.
No, there there are There are men that
are rebellious. AND I'LL COME BECAUSE
I'll still teach on what I call the
seven spirits that stir the waters.
Because there are also people who come
and mess up how THE ORGANIZATION IS. THE
FACT THAT WE WE CANNOT PAY EMPHASIS OVER
SOME MATTER, it doesn't mean they are
not important. Is someone getting me?
SO, THERE MUST BE A BALANCE OF
COMMUNICATION. AND THEN THE FINAL ONE,
"NOR SOUGHT WHAT was lost, but with
force and cruelty you have ruled them."
So, there is those who are driven away
and those who are lost.
So, you have five people, the sick, the
wounded, the broken, the driven away,
and the lost.
So, the the three could be in church.
The the the the the weak,
the sick, the broken could be in church,
but there are also those WE NEED TO GO
FURTHER AND begin to look for them.
There's a lady I met
in England. She used to serve with us.
And I had to apologize to her because I
know what was done to her.
I told her, "I'm sorry." Because as a
leader, I have the responsibility to
seek
those who are lost.
It doesn't matter the distance.
Hallelujah.
You know, the Bible says, "If anyone of
you
misleads
these innocent children of mine." The
word is mislead.
It is better This is Jesus suggesting
the method of death.
It is better that that man
a stone will be tied on his head
on his neck with a rope, and you drown
him in the water.
When you look at the graphics of that
picture, it tells you how valuable and
the value God puts on people.
Let's continue.
So, these are the Tell your neighbor,
but these people are in touch.
Please, just tell that neighbor, you
might be surprised you are sitting next
to one that was lost.
And there are six things
that describe a sheep.
Six things that describe a sheep.
And this is the reason why Jesus called
us the sheep
or the sheep of his flock. NUMBER ONE,
EVERY SHEEP has a shepherd.
Every sheep has a shepherd.
>> [snorts]
>> Jeremiah chapter number three and verse
15.
Every sheep has a shepherd.
And I checked out and I discovered
it is possible to have
um
a not not a strayed
but a wild sheep.
In Jeremiah, the Bible says, "And I will
give you shepherds."
So, the Lord is speaking to the flock.
He's saying, "I will give you shepherds
according to my heart."
According to
So, the Lord is the one who knows the
kind of shepherd a sheep needs.
It is not the sheep that appoints the
shepherd.
>> [snorts]
>> IT IS THE LORD THAT APPOINTS A SHEPHERD
for the sheep.
AND IT IS ACCORDING TO HIS HEART. And
then he says,
"Who will feed you with knowledge and
understanding?"
SO, [snorts]
THE FIRST SIGN THAT THE LORD loves you
and he has
taken care of you as a sheep is THAT HE
WILL PLANT you under a shepherd WHO
FEEDS YOU,
NOT FEEDS FROM YOU.
And what do they feed you?
Not food.
SO, I DON'T NEED A BALES OF FARISEON
SUNDAY.
SO, THAT YOU CAN BECOME GENUINE MEMBERS.
THAT EVERY DAY I TALK to my wife and
ELIJAH AND SAY, "10 BALES SO THAT I CAN
FEED." NO, NO. WE FEED YOU WITH
KNOWLEDGE, NUMBER ONE, AND
UNDERSTANDING.
SO, I KNOW THE DAY I WILL FACE THE
SHEPHERD OF SHEPHERDS, I WILL BE JUDGED
BY THE QUALITY OF food I was giving you.
Those who have studied nutrition, you
know
growth is dependent on the diet you eat.
AND THE KIND OF FOOD YOU EAT CAN GIVE
YOU STRENGTH, IMMUNITY, and even
longevity of life.
SO, THE LORD UNDERSTANDS THAT IF I HAVE
TO GIVE YOU THE RIGHT SHEPHERD, HE MUST
HAVE THE RIGHT FOOD, WHICH IS THE right
knowledge and the right understanding.
So, we can be feeding YOU DEMONOLOGY.
AND THAT DOES NOT GENERATE IMMUNITY
against darkness. YOU WILL SUFFER.
YOU WILL NEVER EAT FROM PLATES THAT ARE
made in India.
You will never use spoons that are made
in China because that's the god of the
dragon. India is the god of the tiger.
SO, YOU WILL END UP SEEING THE DEVIL IN
EVERYTHING.
BUT THE MOMENT WE GIVE YOU JESUS, YOU
DEVELOP immunity against satanic
attacks.
They say in the bank you are taught how
to count original notes, not fake.
So, the more you interact with original,
the day you touch fake, you'll know, no.
So, but the church has done differently.
We are teaching people about fake notes,
so they don't even know the original cuz
they have handled fake.
But it ought to be vice versa. So, every
sheep has a shepherd. Look at Psalm 23.
What is the role of that shepherd?
This is what we call the shepherd psalm.
This is David writing this psalm.
And and David positioned himself now as
a sheep unto the Lord.
>> [snorts]
>> And part of this psalm is what is a very
powerful psalm. This is not a Sunday
school psalm. This is a pastoral psalm.
The name the Lord there means the owner.
The Lord means the owner.
Anytime the Lord introduces him in this
title, he's coming as the owner. He said
unto Pharaoh, "Tell Pharaoh that the
Lord is in need of Israel."
BUT WHEN HE REVEALED HIMSELF TO MOSES,
HE REVEALED himself in a different
order. Who shall I tell them that you
are? Tell them, "I am that I am." BUT TO
PHARAOH, TELL HIM THE LORD. WHY? Pharaoh
thinks he owns Israel, but I own Israel
and I own Egypt.
SO, TELL PHARAOH THE OWNER. SO, THE NAME
THE LORD HERE MEANS the owner. So, the
Lord, the owner, IS MY SHEPHERD.
I SHALL NOT WANT. Because if the owner
IS MY SHEPHERD AND THAT OWNER is the
Lord Yahweh, how can I be in luck? And
then look at the second part.
He makes me to lie down in green
pastures. He makes me. BECAUSE THE ROLE
OF A SHEPHERD IS TO FEED THE FLOCK.
NOW, THIS PSALM IS SO DEEP because
Israel is a desert.
And David WAS WRITING THE PSALM WHILE in
Israel.
Meaning that FOR YOU TO FIND GREEN
PASTURES IN A DESERT is a miracle.
So, what is the order here?
THE ORDER IS VERY SIMPLE.
THE SHEPHERD WILL LEAVE the flock
and leave them in a safe place and
secure,
maybe at night, and the shepherd will
walk out.
AND HE WILL GO SEARCHING ALL OVER THE
DESERT.
HE WILL check out
and move
and check BECAUSE IT IS THE ROLE OF THE
SHEPHERD TO LOOK for food.
So, HE WILL GO AND SEARCH AND CHECK AND
CHECK AND DISCOVER, "WOW, there's green
pasture.
There is water. This is what my flock
needs." So, the shepherd will go
for the flock.
Hallelujah.
Now, Pastor Kevin, come.
Pastor
William, Pastor Ronnie Bish,
uh
come.
So,
the flock is here.
The flock is here.
So,
you don't send the flock
to look for food. And your work is where
where
That's not how
you lead a
>> [laughter]
[gasps]
>> Then, SUDDENLY YOU STUMBLE
ON SOME GREEN AREA. And then now you
settle there and you sit down. That's
not the Bible. The Bible is the sheep
must be addressed.
Hallelujah.
Now, this will help you understand why
the sheep
cannot abandon the shepherd and the
shepherd cannot abandon the sheep.
Because the role of the shepherd is to
look for pasture.
When [snorts] he finds the pasture, he
comes for the sheep.
That's why the Bible says, "He leadeth
me." Leadeth. The word lead simply means
someone is following.
So, the shepherd is ahead of the sheep.
And the sheep follows the shepherd
because they have they have interacted
for a while and the sheep know the
shepherd.
And if the sheep are many, all they need
to do there is that long stick that a
The used to have because a shepherd, as
you see, has two things. He has a rod
and a staff. So, if they see the
shepherd, they follow the head of that
stick. They know the shepherd is leading
us. The shepherd is leading us. And then
the shepherd now allows them in green
And the Bible says, he makes me lie
down. It's a language of comfort. He
doesn't harass me because remember, we
have the broken,
the wounded,
the sick.
Is someone getting me?
And so now, in this in this
conversation, he now comes AND SAYS, HE
NOW ALSO
LOOK at that song. Look at that song.
He makes ME TO LIE DOWN in green
pastures because the role of a shepherd
is to feed the flock.
So, a good pastor is not the one who
pays your rent when your house is
closed.
A good PASTOR IS THE ONE THAT FEEDS you
to a level your house can never be
closed BECAUSE YOU HAVE MATURED, you
have capacity. SO, YOU DON'T COME A GOOD
PASTOR WHEN YOU ARE fixing the issues of
men. You become A GOOD PASTOR WHEN YOU
FEED THE FLOCK TO A POINT THEY LACK
NOTHING.
NOW, YOU SEE THE CHURCH HAS MADE US LOOK
GOOD.
We are not saying we don't have a place
for the ministry of mercy. But even
before mercy,
even as we help you, we know you are
going to be a testimony. Something will
happen. We don't meet on mercy, we meet
on knowledge
and understanding.
And so now, after lying in pastures
green,
guess what happens.
Stay there. Number two is very serious.
HE MAKES ME TO LIE DOWN IN GREEN
PASTURES. He leads ME BESIDES
THAT ONE still is very powerful.
Because
There are two things that scatter flock.
One is war and conflict. Sheep Most of
the sheep have no horns.
So they DON'T UNDERSTAND COMBAT.
THAT'S WHY when there is
in leadership
The first thing the sheep will do is
scatter.
Because they don't know how to fight,
they don't know how to attack the but
they don't know.
The second thing that sheep does, they
never drink from running water and
disturbed water. You never see sheep
drinking from a waterfall.
Those are the two things that scatter
sheep.
Battles.
Conflicts among the shepherds.
And that's why the Bible says, I will
strike
the shepherd
because THE ENEMY KNOWS ONCE THE
SHEPHERD IS ATTACKED, ONCE THERE IS
CONFLICT among the shepherds and they
attack each other, sheep does not
understand any other language other than
to scatter for safety.
And guess what happens when sheep
scatters?
Sheep number one goes.
The second one goes. The other one goes.
They are now vulnerable to attacks.
A wolf does not need to struggle. It
just need to devour them one by one. And
this is what the devil loves when we
have a scattered congregation because
our unity is false even in battle.
Now go back. And that's why I said there
are seven spirits that disturb the
waters.
Seven.
That disturb the waters.
And I'll teach them. Number one is
called the spirit of
the leviathan spirit.
The leviathan spirit. The spirit of
gossip, malice, leviathan.
Number two, Jezebelic spirit.
Jezebel.
People who never submit under authority.
Number three, Absalom spirit.
Absalom.
Misrepresentation at the gates.
I can tell you we have seen great
ministries scatter
because they ignore these things.
Leviathan.
Jezebel.
Absalom.
Number four, the spirit of Korah.
Those that rise from cliques and fight
authorities.
So someone has a problem.
My pastor builds such a Sunday school.
And sometimes they make sense.
Number five.
This one is a very it's a it's a very
demonic one.
Jannes and Jambres.
The spirit of Jannes and Jambres.
This is
These are people they they don't fight.
These ones oppose.
You can sense they're opposing.
And they fight in three levels. They
oppose.
When their opposition does not work,
they camouflage and they become one of
you.
So that now they they don't oppose, they
infiltrate.
It was the spirit of Jannes and Jambres
that built the golden calf.
They opposed Moses.
When they realized they could not oppose
him any further, they now infiltrated.
The Bible says there were more than 400
Egyptians that left Egypt with the
children of Israel. No promise, no
covenant, but they were part of that
entourage.
When they arrived in the wilderness,
they exalted the golden calf. It is
called
battle through infiltration.
And one of the ways to conquer
infiltration is to You see, spirits do
not dominate where they're exposed.
The enemy survives in camouflage.
So the moment you begin to open the eyes
of people, those spirits are defeated.
They become weak.
Jannes and Jambres.
These are people Some of them are
witches that come to church and position
themselves as diviners, as prophets.
And let me warn you, please,
any ministry that is not of the pastors
I mentioned here, anyone who prophesies
to you, even if it's in a family group,
that's not our spirit. We don't prophesy
in private. We don't prophesy in phone
calls. We don't call people and say,
"Sijui kwa nini Mungu amenipatia mzigo
ya kukuombeanga. Nimeona vita na
nimeamua kukuombea." That's not our
order.
And if you are if you get a prophecy and
you give a tithe and you are bound, that
is not us. That is you and the person.
Because as we grow, we don't know. The
Bible says Paul assembles sticks and a
viper.
And that viper looked like the sticks.
It is until fire intensified
that they realize this is not a This is
not a stick. It is not there to warm us
in Limuru. It is there to bite us.
That's why our role is to intensify
fire. I tell my worshipers, you don't
learn singing from the altar. You build
capacity in the secret place. On the
altar, you release virtue.
We don't become fathers by training you
vocals here. No, that's not fatherhood.
That's slaughter.
The battles of these altar are fierce.
You might stand one day and confront
what you are confronting. You'll not be
able to fight.
So, where have we reached?
Jannes and Jambres.
Jambres. They're still number six.
Yes?
Balaam.
The spirit of Balaam.
And this one is a bad one.
It's brought by congregation.
This is where the congregation does not
want preaching. They want miracles.
When you begin TO SAY, "I PROPHESY IN
THE NEXT 7 DAYS, MONEY COMETH." SOMEONE
COMES WITH 100,000 and lays it on the
altar and say, "Prophesy, papa.
Prophesy." Balaam.
Go deeper.
When I'm teaching SUCH MYSTERIES, NO ONE
IS STANDING TO SAY AMEN. YOU CAN SEE THE
WAY YOU ARE.
When I begin TO SAY SEVEN DOORS OF
WEALTH, YOU SEE SOMEONE standing with
all their [music] Bibles. Hallelujah.
That's my word. And I don't know They
have a counter as mhm.
That's my word.
Glory.
I'M NOT SAYING IT'S BAD TO RECEIVE THE
WORD. TELL YOUR NEIGHBOR, NEIGHBOR.
LET ME LOOK FOR THE SEVENTH ONE.
MY SHEEP DON'T LEAVE THERE.
Because I want to teach something.
Are you understanding?
Let me show you the seventh one.
Is the spirit of the Nicolaitans.
The spirit of the Nicolaitans is where
we begin to mix
Christianity
and other things.
Where we teach you new age.
We teach you how to open the third eye
of the spirit, but through witchcraft.
It is not the Bible. So, we are mixing.
So, those are the seven spirits. And
it's still a part of what I wanted to
teach. So, in Psalms 23
Psalms 23, sheep drink from still waters
and not rapid or running water. Sheep
run from rapid water and bottles.
Let's look at that Psalm.
My sheep, are you still there?
So, so, so they are enjoying.
They are enjoying.
Because you can have a scattered soul.
And you can see the operation still
happen in the place of feeding and
drinking.
Because water
water carries three benefits to an
animal.
The first thing that water does, water
quenches your thirst.
You know, there is a specific thirst
even if you take tea.
It just demands water.
So, water number one does what? Quenches
your
thirst. Number two, water refreshes you.
You can come out of a long journey, long
flight, and after a shower, you feel
like your body has come back.
So, water quenches your thirst. Water
refreshes you, but there is something
that water does number three.
Water makes you lose your scent.
For those who love movies of
investigations,
and prison breaks,
a bus, let us out.
Oh, this one is a very good shepherd. He
comes in the Masai.
He He was He was in the narrow cooker
and I might come home tonight.
Now,
so
So, listen.
The third thing that water does is that
it makes you lose your scent.
When you look at these movies where
people are doing prison break,
and they release dogs, sniffing dogs.
What they do is that they get one of the
garments of the prisoner, and they give
it to the dog. They make the dog sniff.
Because of the memory of instincts in
the dog, that smell remains, and it
becomes a mark. So, as dog is looking,
it leads the people where it can locate
the scent.
Many animals hunt by scent.
So, a hyena can sense
there is a sheep that has passed here,
and begin to pursue that scent.
What happens at that hour when
you jump in water, and that's why you
find when those thieves when they jump
in the river, the dog will come and then
turn around because now I have lost
scent.
The one I was following, I cannot
pursue.
SO, THERE IS SOMETHING when the flock
receives the right water. Where not only
can they drink and get refreshed, but
they can also bathe and lose their scent
so that the pursuit of the enemy can
come to AN END. THE WATER MUST BE STILL.
Someone getting me?
And now and he says, "He leads me."
The Lord now.
Still reading. He leads me
in the path of
righteousness.
The Lord will never lead you to error.
And what does he say? "FOR HIS NAME'S
SAKE." WHAT IS THE NAME OF THE LORD? The
character of God.
Anywhere you SEE IN THE BIBLE, THE BIBLE
recording that because of his name's
sake, HE NEVER DID ONE, TWO, THREE, it
is whereby God was being put [music] at
a place and his character was being
challenged. And he is the unchanging
God.
So, he cannot change in that situation.
HE CAN ONLY CHANGE THE SITUATION.
BECAUSE HE CAN'T CHANGE TO ACCOMMODATE
THE SITUATION.
SO, you are sick and he's the healer.
So, so, so, for his name's sake,
he he he cannot allow you to die with A
DISEASE.
HE HAS to heal you because he's A
HEALER.
AND THAT HE IS, NO MATTER what happens.
So, when you see the name, his name's
sake, it's a language of
his character. He can't go away. And
then now he comes. Eh eh.
Continue. I love these arms.
I know we sing that final. Yeah, though
I WALK THROUGH THE VALLEY
OF
THE SHADOW OF DEATH. NOT THROUGH THE
VALLEY AND
>> [snorts]
>> THE VALLEY OF VALLEYS A PLACE OF
WARFARE.
A PLACE OF DEFEAT. And he's putting it
as a possibility. NOW, WHO IS THAT?
DAVID IS the one declaring. And what has
David told you? That the Lord is my
shepherd. What does THE SHEPHERD DO? THE
SHEPHERD leads me. So, I'm always behind
THE SHEPHERD. SO, WHAT HAPPENS? EVEN
THOUGH SO, IF I HAVE TO WALK IN THAT
VALLEY, THE SHEPHERD HAS ALREADY WALKED
IN THAT VALLEY. BECAUSE AS A GOOD SHEEP,
I DON'T FOLLOW THE AS A GOOD SHEEP, I
FOLLOW THE SHEPHERD. SO, IF THE SHADOW
OF DEATH CAN TAKE OUT THE SHEPHERD, I'LL
ALSO GO OUT.
>> YEAH.
>> SO, THE LAST STATEMENT OF THAT WORD
IS NOT A MOTIVATIONAL [music] SPEAKING.
EVEN THOUGH I WALK THROUGH THE VALLEY of
the shadow OF DEATH, I SHALL FEAR NO
EVIL. PLEASE READ IT because today
you'll understand this is not a Sunday
school song.
>> Yes.
>> I
I THOUGH I WALK, IT'S A POSSIBILITY.
BECAUSE THE SHEPHERD CANNOT LEAD YOU IN
SOME AREAS. BUT, IF THE DEVIL BECOMES
CARELESS ENOUGH
TO INTRODUCE SOME DIMENSIONS, I KNOW
THAT THE LORD IS MY SHEPHERD. THOUGH I
WALK THROUGH THE VALLEY OF THE SHADOW OF
DEATH. SO, DEATH IS THERE THERE. BECAUSE
YOU CAN'T HAVE A SHADOW IF THE IMAGE IS
NOT THERE. SO, DEATH IS THERE, BUT LIFE
IS ALSO THERE. BECAUSE JESUS SAID, I AM
THE WAY, THE TRUTH, AND THE LIFE. THOUGH
I WALK THROUGH THE VALLEY OF THE SHADOW
OF DEATH. I'M SPEAKING TO SOMEBODY
TODAY. IT'S NOT ABOUT WHERE YOU ARE
WALKING. IT'S ABOUT WHO ARE YOU WALKING
WITH IN THAT AREA? IF THE LORD BE BY MY
SIDE, WHO CAN BE AGAINST ME? MAY THE
LORD HAVE EYES THAT MY ENEMIES MAY BE
SCATTERED. SO, ENEMIES ARE THERE, BUT
THE [screaming] RISING OF THE SHEPHERD
WILL SCATTER THE ENEMIES.
And he continues. Please give me the
scripture.
Give me the scripture.
I know we are looking good. Let's stick
on scripture.
For you are with me.
I will fear
>> No evil.
>> I will fear
>> YEAH, FROM TODAY
NO WITCH,
NO DEVIL. KAYABA SHATAYA.
THE LORD SAYS HE WILL BE WITH YOU.
HE NEVER SAID YOU'LL NOT GO THROUGH THE
WATER. YOU WILL GO THROUGH VALLEYS, BUT
I WILL BE WITH YOU.
I WILL FEAR NO EVIL. SOMEBODY LIFT UP
YOUR HAND AND SAY FROM TODAY
I FEAR IS NOT MY PORTION. THEY WILL COME
IN ONE WAY, BUT BE SCATTERED IN SEVEN
DIFFERENT WAYS. NOT BECAUSE OF ME, BUT
BECAUSE OF THE SHEPHERD.
HEY.
AND THEN
HE COMES AND SAYS, DO YOU KNOW WHY HE'S
CONFIDENT? He says you are lord
and your staff. There are two of them.
This is the staff.
You don't discipline or control
the flock with a rod.
The rod is for evil.
When a lion comes, you show it the rod.
When a sheep tries to go astray, you
show it the staff.
Are you getting it?
So, it is key as a shepherd to know when
to use the rod.
IF I REALIZE THERE IS A SERPENT WITHIN
THE FLOCK,
I will show the serpent the rod, but
I'll show the flock
the staff.
And the staff is for direction.
Hallelujah. You went there. I know you
want to get married,
>> HALLELUJAH.
WE WE WE WE ARE RESTORING YOU WITH
ORDER. BUT BUT be a GOOGLE WITH A
CERTAIN WEIGHT. It is painful, but it IS
IMPORTANT. HE DOESN'T SAY THEY THEY THEY
PUNISH ME. They say they comfort me.
Because the Bible says the Lord
chastises them THAT HE LOVES. ONE OF THE
SIGNS THAT GOD LOVES YOU IS WHEN he
takes time to discipline [music]
you.
Do you KNOW WHEN A MOTHER IS
DISCIPLINING A CHILD, IT'S NOT A SIGN OF
HATRED?
IT'S PROJECTED LOVE. THAT I LOVE YOU TOO
MUCH TO SEE YOU GO OFF.
I LOVE YOU TOO MUCH TO SEE YOU MESS UP
WHEN I'M HERE. It is a sign of care. SO
THERE ARE CERTAIN REBUKES THAT come from
heaven. They need to take you back home
smiling. YOU KNOW ANY GOD BUT WHEN I
NEED to come back. YOU KNOW WE LOVE
BLESSINGS. IF GOD SPEAKS AND IT'S A
REBUKE, it's an encouragement. It means
he was thinking about you. IT'S BETTER
TO RECEIVE A REBUKE than silence.
That two years God has never spoken. I
tell you I need a rebuke. At least need
you to come back home again.
>> [snorts]
>> They comfort me. Hallelujah. Tell your
neighbor neighbor.
There is a time for roads.
And a time for?
So when I begin to see wolves
trying to attack my sheep I don't
negotiate with the road.
You know what you want to know about
your calling? You know about your
calling?
>> [laughter]
>> It is something in Greek.
Edwin.
That Matthew calling is a Greek Rungu.
IT IS SHAPELESS.
AND THAT THING CAN DAMAGE ANYTHING. So
that's what you show the enemy.
Hallelujah.
Pastor Ronnie I want to know.
>> [laughter]
>> I WANT TO KNOW.
GO AND BRING IT. WE NEED WE NEED WE NEED
TO UNDERSTAND THE mystery of the We need
We need WE NEED TO UNDERSTAND the
mystery OF THE OF THE LORD. TELL YOUR
NEIGHBOR FROM TODAY,
the Lord is thy shepherd.
And then we love the second part. Look
at the other part.
I know you Now, the problem is that
you prepare
a table
before
in the presence
Now, listen. Do you know what the Lord
is saying? The business of enemies is
not your business.
It I know they're my enemies, but your
enemies are my enemies. The enemy of the
flock is the enemy of the shepherd.
That's why when a shepherd entertains
wolves, the flock will be comfortable
with wolves.
I was given a story of someone who came,
became a member, and then took a loan,
and then he left.
That's a wolf.
Was trying to masquerade as a
sheep.
And so, when we discovered there's a
There's a young man we called because he
he had moved from That was an original
wolf.
He had eaten a few flock, and now he was
now moving towards Vault Church.
So, we gathered with Pastor Jimmy. We
told him, "Even seeing you near that
road that comes to Vault Church, we
don't want to see you. And if we see
you, we will anoint you and lay hands a
certain perpendicular angle, descending
with certain frequencies."
And it's not to reach to release
impartations.
The Bible says there are some demons
that live by
Because when sheep is comfortable with
wolves, it
Are you getting it?
And then now
I know. Let's continue. Please, let the
scripture remain there.
You anoint my head with oil.
My cup
Those are two different things.
The reason why the shepherd anoints the
sheep with oil on the head
is because there are those small
animals, insects, that keep on
Thy rod
>> [laughter]
>> AND THY STAFF, THEY SHALL DO WHAT?
>> OH, YOU'RE A SHEPHERD. IT'S A SHEPHERD'S
STAFF. Even me. Hallelujah.
So, listen.
So, when the Bible speaks about
anointing the head with oil, it was a
language of making sure nothing disturbs
you.
Keep on doing like this.
You know, I keep on doing like this so
that the noise can scare away the flies.
But when there is oil,
the
animal slides or the animal sticks. So,
they cannot disturb. And you can see
it's the head.
The head.
Control center.
HEADQUARTERS.
THE CENTER OF ORDERS. IF THE HEAD IS
OKAY, THAT'S WHY JESUS SAID, "I am a
man."
Peter realized
Messiah
>> So, he anoints my head, but when you go
to Now, the the the the other time Jesus
gets into a Jewish house, a Pharisee
house.
And a woman comes AND
POURS AND CRIES on the feet. And and she
cries and pours oil. And and the man
Simeon, he says, "If this man knew who
this woman is."
And Jesus is there just waiting for the
woman to finish the drama. And then
Jesus looks at and says, "There are two
people. One was forgotten, less dead
than the other one." I said, "I came to
your house.
You didn't even anoint my head with
oil."
Because in the culture of the Jews, when
an important man comes to your house,
you wash his feet because he has
traveled a long journey. You wash HIS
HANDS. YOU WIPE HIS FACE AND anoint his
head. So, this is also a language of
heaven saying, "You are a VVIP
in the house OF YOUR FATHER." THAT'S WHY
IT IS THE LORD, THE SHEPHERD, IS THE ONE
THAT ANOINTS YOUR HEAD with
The language of preparing a table is a
language of
You know, you don't eat in war.
It's a language of the battle is won.
You don't have the luxury of cooking in
war.
But when the battle is settled, you can
eat.
And then he says, "My cup
runs over." It's a language of perpetual
supply.
Remember, it begins from the Lord is.
Don't forget, these are benefits of
being shepherded.
A sheep has a shepherd.
Sheep does not drink from disturbed
waters.
The seven spirits that disturb the
water. And now, you I quote the one you
like quoting.
I know this one you know. Now you can
quote it.
>> [clears throat]
>> Uh-huh.
Now tell your neighbor, before you quote
this scripture
YOU NEED TO ASK YOURSELF
DO I HAVE A SHEPHERD?
NUMBER TWO
AS I BEGIN TO CONCLUDE, sheep has a
sharp memory.
They have SHARP MEMORY.
THEY CANNOT FORGET THEIR SHEPHERD.
SO EVERY SHEEP HAS A SHEPHERD. Psalms
23, Jeremiah 3 and verse 15. SHEEP HAS
SHARP MEMORY. THEY CANNOT FORGET their
shepherd.
But
it is not JUST ANY SHEPHERD. IT'S THE
SHEPHERD THAT HAS BEEN feeding them
taking care of THE SHEEP
HANDLING THEM.
SO THE SHEPHERD MUST BE SO AVAILABLE TO
THE SHEEP, NOT A ONE-OFF APPOINTMENT,
BUT A DAILY APPOINTMENT SO THAT THE
SHEEP CAN FAMILIARIZE with the voice of
the shepherd.
John chapter number 10 from verse 1 to
5.
These are very powerful thing.
It says, "Most assuredly I say to you,
he who does not enter the sheepfold by
the door, but climbs up some other way,
the same is a thief and a robber.
But he who enters by the door is THE
SHEPHERD OF
THE SHEEP.
TO HIM THE DOORKEEPER OPENS AND THE
SHEEP HEARS
HIS VOICE.
BECAUSE THE SHEEP MAY NOT HAVE A MEMORY
of your clothes, but they cannot forget
your voice. AND HE CALLS HIS OWN SHEEP
BY name and leads them out. Hallelujah.
There is a relationship between the
shepherd and the sheep. He calls. He
calls. He calls the SHEEP BY NAME. THE
SHEEP KNOW HIS VOICE. HALLELUJAH. And
when he brings out his own sheep, he
goes before them. Have you seen the
order? AND THE SHEEP FOLLOW HIM, FOR
THEY KNOW
HIS VOICE. LET'S LOOK at five.
Yet they WILL BE BY NO MEANS DO WHAT?
FOLLOW A STRANGER, BUT will flee from
him, for they do not know the voice of
strangers. Hold this. Listen, SOME OF
YOU ARE FOLLOWING VOICES of strangers
online.
>> [snorts]
>> A good sheep is a faithful to the voice
of the shepherd.
HEY, SOME OF YOU EVEN YOU STOP TITHE IN.
YOU NOW TITHE IN other churches. Though
you come physically here.
YOU ARE A STRANGE SHEEP.
WE NEED to come FOR YOU.
WHERE YOU ARE TITHE IN, THAT SHEEP
CANNOT TITHE ANYWHERE.
AND A GOOD SHEPHERD DOES NOT BRING THE
WHOLE FOOD.
He brings portions, what you can handle
at a time.
You know, when we go when we are guest
preachers, we always preach the whole
Bible.
BECAUSE WE ONLY HAVE 1 hour or 2 hours
to preach. BUT AT HOME, YOU CAN'T PREACH
THE WHOLE BIBLE, ONE point at a time.
BECAUSE YOU CAN'T feed like that. It is
precept upon precept. Is someone getting
me?
So, sheep have a sharp memory. They know
of the shepherd. YOU REMEMBER MARY
MAGDALENE?
MARY MAGDALENE IS LOOKING for the for
Jesus, the body of Christ.
And he sees a man, and he thinks the man
is actually a one of the gardeners
there. And he goes to the man, MEANING
THAT HE CAN'T RECOGNIZE THE MAN.
And he asked the man, "Where did you lay
HIS BODY?" AND THEN JESUS CALLED CALLED
HER AND SAID, "MARY." WHEN MARY HEARD
THE VOICE OF JESUS, SHE SAID RABBONI.
BECAUSE THE FACT THAT MARY COULD NOT
recognize Jesus after resurrection, she
knew the voice because for 3 years she
was hanging around with that voice.
The sheep know my voice because the
shepherd takes care of the sheep. NUMBER
THREE,
SHEEP WHEN THEY MATURE, THEY KNOW HOW TO
KEEP BOUNDARIES.
MATURE SHEEP KNOW HOW TO KEEP
BOUNDARIES.
NOW, THIS IS THE MYSTERY OF the 99.
Jesus says in the book of Luke 15, there
are three lost things in Luke 15. Lost
sheep, lost coin, and lost son.
IT'S A IT'S A VERY DEEP BOOK, Luke 15.
And the sinners drew near to him to hear
him. You can see two people came to
Jesus, tax collectors and sinners.
ANOINTINGS ATTRACT CRITICIZERS and
benefactors.
So, YOU HAVE AN OPTION EITHER TO FOCUS
ON THOSE WHO criticize or those who are
benefiting. But, look at the next one.
And the Pharisees and scribes
complaining saying, "This man receives
sinners and eats with them." Every
anointed man will attract tax collectors
and sinners.
If you WANT TO SPEND YOUR WHOLE TIME on
Tik Tok PROVING YOU ARE CALLED, "THIS
MAN WILL NEVER CHANGE." Please bless
those that you are called to bless. Take
care of your shepherd of your sheep
flock. So, he spoke this parable to them
saying,
"What a man of you having 100 sheep, if
he loses one of them, does not leave the
99 in the wilderness and go after the
one which is lost until he finds it?"
So, they understand the parable because
in the natural, when you have when you
have many sheep, sometimes you have a
mature one.
Okay?
And a mature sheep knows the boundaries.
Now, in the In those days, they didn't
have fences.
So, they would take the sheep to feed,
but it was the role of the shepherd to
now come
and and and and and and as they're
feeding, as they're feeding, when they
reach a certain area, he will now begin
to tell them, "No, no, go go go go." So,
the mature sheep will know the boundary
of feeding.
Are you getting it? But now, there is
one young hungry sheep.
>> [laughter]
>> So, as they are feeding, as they are
feeding, ONE HUNGRY SHEEP DECIDES to
open portals
and start idioms. So, the sheep is
feeding, forecast feeding, BUT WHATEVER
IT'S FEEDING IS NOT IN the boundaries.
So, WHEN WHEN THE SHEPHERD REALIZES THAT
ONE HAS LEFT, THIS IS THE LOST ONE.
MANY TIMES IT'S NOT BACKSLIDING, going
to the world.
IT IS GOING OUT OF THE place of feeding.
The jurisdiction.
AND [snorts] YOU CAN STUDY AND GO and go
and go. By the time you are preaching,
you are not preaching the Bible, you're
preaching demons.
And so, what the shepherd does, he
knows, "Because I have a mature sheep,
it can take care of the 99 as I pursue
that immature that left."
Am I communicating?
BECAUSE THE MATURE SHEEP KNOW THE
parameters of feeding and they can take
care of the incoming.
SO, THEY'RE THE ONES THAT LEAD IN
FEEDING AND THEY'LL REACH A PLACE and
continue and reach a place and continue
BECAUSE THE BECAUSE ONE OF THE THINGS IS
THAT SHEEP WORK IN TEAMS AND MOST OF THE
TIMES THEY are led by the mature.
SO, IF THE MATURE IS NOT GROUNDED
ENOUGH, IT CAN MISLEAD THE OTHERS.
BUT SOMETIMES THE YOUNG SHEEP ARE HASTY
AND THEY go out of the flock.
AND SO, THE MASTER KNOWING THAT THIS IS
A SHEEP AND NOT A GOAT, AND BY GETTING
OUT OF THE BOUNDARY IT CAN BE DEVOURED
BY WOLVES AND WILD ANIMALS, THE MASTER
WHO IS A SHEPHERD WILL NOW ARISE WITH
his
rod.
And he cannot leave
staff.
Because
I need to deal
and restore
the sheep back to
the fold so that
which are not mysteries.
So so that's why we need to mature
people.
Number six, is it number six?
Okay, let me give you an order. Every
sheep has a shepherd number one.
Sheep has sharp memory number two.
They cannot forget their shepherd. Sheep
when they mature they know how to keep
boundaries. Sheep walk in team number
four.
Sheep drink from still waters and not
rapid or running waters. Number five,
that came before.
Sheep drink from still waters and not
rapid waters or running waters.
Number six.
Number five, okay, whatever yours is.
Whatever you are.
So what happens is that
the Lord must make sure that
this mature flock, once in a while, is
the one that is trained on the
boundaries of feeding.
Bonas feel.
And once they are trained on the
boundaries of feeding, it means they
will perpetually be there.
And when we come to sheep,
yeah, number five. Now this is just a
point. Look at the book of John 21:15
and verse 17. There are three categories
of sheep.
There are three categories of sheep.
There are three of them.
John 21:15 and 17.
Let's all read.
So when they had eaten breakfast, Jesus
said to Simon Peter, "Simon, son of
Jonah, do you love me more than this?"
This is after Peter had gone fishing.
So, he's looking at the harvest and
asking him this. He said to him, "Yes,
Lord. You know that I love you." He said
to him, "Feed
my
lamb." The first category.
A lamb.
A young
sheep
that needs tender caring.
That is not strong.
Not very stable.
And this one, there are times when you
feed it and there are times when you
carry it.
Have you ever seen the picture of Jesus
being called the good shepherd?
He's not having a mature sheep. He's
always having a lamb.
This is one that you can put on the
bosom. Do you know why the bosom? The
bosom, the Bible speaks of Abraham's
bosom. The bosom is a place of love and
fellowship.
So, these are the young ones. You don't
You don't rebuke. You don't kill. You
don't scatter these ones.
Praise the Lord.
You have to take care. They are tender.
They are born recently.
They are AFRAID TO DO WRONG.
THEY ARE NOT BIG REVELATION. The book of
Revelation.
You walk with them slowly.
Take care of that lamb.
>> [laughter]
>> Hallelujah.
Yes, you don't harass them. You have to
be very sensitive. And then he come and
ask him again.
He said
He said to him He said to him again
second time, "Simon, son of Jonah, do
you love me?" He said to him, "Yes,
Lord. You know that I love you." He said
to him, "Tend my sheep." So, this lamb
must grow and become a sheep.
Now, listen. The the word here. It's not
feed.
It's tend.
Take away the excess wool.
At this level, you can't tend. This
level, you feed to grow.
At this level, you tend.
You tend. And And you see, it is this
level that the sheep benefits the
shepherd.
Because when you take away excess wool,
you can make a jacket.
You don't skin a lamb.
But the lamb you have fed that has grown
to become a sheep,
you now begin to tend. Tending is in two
levels. It's now teaching the person
mannerism of Christianity, how to
present yourself, how to walk
practicality. We call them practical We
call Christian living.
And guess what? You are now tending.
Because if this man does not allow us to
tend him, the wool will be too heavy on
him, and it will hinder growth.
So, we must Anything, we must take care
of the clothes. We must take care so
that we can also now go to the next
level.
Because we can't feed you if we've not
tended you.
The third one, let's continue.
He said to him the third time, "Simon,
son of Jonah, do you love Peter was
grieved because he said to him that that
time, do you love me? If you're a good
Bible student reader, you already know
Peter denied Jesus three times.
So, this is restoration of Peter.
And then you begin to see as a shepherd,
the Lord does not say you love him by
how you shout. It's by how you take care
of the sheep.
And now he tells him, and he said to
him, "Lord, you know all things. You
know that I love you." Jesus said to
him, "Feed
my sheep."
Now, you have in every congregation, you
have lamb.
You have sheep that need tending, and
you have sheep.
My spiritual father told me
>> [laughter]
>> So,
you can see how hard our work is.
As a shepherd every Sunday,
I must feed the lambs that are here.
I must
take care of the sheep, and I'm also
take care. These are mature, they know
boundaries. Some of them even what
you're preaching, they have heard it.
They don't even say amen. They're
looking at you waiting for new
revelations. It is the new lamb that is
saying, "Wow, that was deep. I've never
heard it." So, they're the ones
encouraging you.
NOW, SOMETIMES YOU HAVE A BIAS TO PREACH
to these ones.
Because they're the ones who sit at the
front.
And sometimes you're preaching and
they're sleeping.
BUT THERE IS A LAMB AT THE BACK HUNGRY
BECAUSE THAT IS WHAT will grow the lamb
>> [music]
>> and make it come to the next level.
And that's why now in our preaching,
when I stand on this altar, I must be
very sensitive to understand that the
Lord has given me sheep, and my main
responsibility is to feed
the sheep. Someone getting it?
NOW,
THE THE DYNAMIC OF THAT, and this is the
error of patterns,
is that the Lord has brought the three.
Now, from this and this, I can benefit
as a shepherd. I can milk this one, and
I can milk this one. I can remove wools
and wools, but my motivation of raising
the lamb was not so that I can milk and
get the wool.
That means if that's my motivation, I'll
never raise a lamb. I'll perpetually
have a relationship with these two
because they benefit me as a shepherd.
Can I now come personal?
So, as to monger about the sheep sana.
Now, this is the error.
In the 21st century,
the shepherd is too busy because the
sheep has refused to take care of the
shepherd. So, the shepherd is too busy
looking for school fees, looking for
rent, looking for all these things. Then
on Saturday, he googles GMO food.
Cuz on Sunday, the sheep wants to feed.
So, I go and listen to one Nigerian
sermon,
one Australian. I make notes of things I
don't even believe.
And I come, and I make sure my monitors
are very high and sound is very high,
and I shout a whole hour
because I did not have enough time to go
and search the pasture for my sheep.
Because I I I also have
responsibilities. I have a child.
I have a wife. I [snorts] have things.
And that's why, when you look at the
Catholic Church, they have mastered the
concept of taking care of their
shepherd.
They make sure you don't marry, so no
children.
And they build for you somewhere called
a parish. They give you a car.
And they even employ chefs. So, the role
of the shepherd is to look for food.
And guess who benefits when the shepherd
has enough time to look for food?
It's the sheep.
One of my mentors rebuked me.
And he told me, "Pastor,
you're traveling a lot.
And sometimes when you go outside there,
you give other people's sheep the meal
of your flock."
The time I traveled with Pastor Kevin, I
preached.
>> [snorts]
>> And from that time, of course, we don't
preach for those envelopes. They're
They're That's That's not our
motivation.
But what I discovered is that And And
I'm speaking this now to the body of
Christ. It is important for the shepherd
to be intentional to look for food for
the sheep.
Because the only job that God has given
us is to feed you.
But it is equally important for the
sheep to take care of the shepherd.
Are you getting it?
Because if the shepherd has no time,
this year I have canceled many meetings
because I felt, "No.
The people God has given me are more
important than the churches I'm going."
So, I said, "Whatever I will preach in
another church, I must have preached it
first in Life Church. They will be the
first consumers.
Unless the heaven opens in another level
in a meeting, but I say these ones will
be the first consumers of the meat and
the food that I carry. That's why
sometimes you see me extending the
service. Let me receive the worshipers.
Can we appreciate this amazing sheep?
Please tell your neighbor from today
be a good sheep. Let me receive the
worshipers. Have you learned something?
Have you learned something? So, now you
understand my role. My role is to do
what? Feed you.
And mine is also to take care of you,
and mine is to also feed you again,
because that's the responsibility that
God has left us with. Just stand up on
your feet. I just want us to release a
chorus. Sometimes when you labor in
teachings, many things are settled. But
the